class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}


List<QuestionModel> EarthSystemEngineering=[
  QuestionModel(question: "1. What is the primary objective of Earth Systems Engineering?",
      options: [
        "To design and manage the complex interactions between natural and engineered systems",
        "To explore Earth's ecosystems",
        "To study geological formations",
        "To develop advanced space exploration techniques"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Earth Systems Engineering aims to design and manage complex interactions between natural and engineered systems."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "2. Which principle does Earth Systems Engineering mainly focus on?",
      options: [
        "Solving universal gravitational problems",
        "Managing the interactions between social and environmental systems",
        "Regulating atmospheric pressure",
        "Developing advanced recycling systems"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The focus of Earth Systems Engineering is on managing interactions between social and environmental systems."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "3. What does 'System Dynamics' refer to in Earth Systems Engineering?",
      options: [
        "Studying Earth's magnetic fields",
        "Analyzing system behavior over time",
        "Developing models for celestial bodies",
        "Studying ocean currents"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "'System Dynamics' involves analyzing system behavior over time in Earth Systems Engineering."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "4. How does Earth Systems Engineering contribute to sustainability?",
      options: [
        "By developing interstellar travel solutions",
        "By studying soil composition",
        "By providing solutions to balance economic, social, and environmental considerations",
        "By managing asteroid mining missions"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "It contributes to sustainability by providing solutions that balance economic, social, and environmental considerations."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "5. What is the primary focus of 'Environmental Risk Assessment' in Earth Systems Engineering?",
      options: [
        "Predicting weather patterns",
        "Assessing the risk of volcanic eruptions",
        "Identifying and managing potential environmental hazards",
        "Developing waste management systems"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "'Environmental Risk Assessment' in Earth Systems Engineering is focused on identifying and managing potential environmental hazards."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "6. How does Earth Systems Engineering relate to space exploration?",
      options: [
        "By creating sustainable ecosystems on other planets",
        "By studying the behavior of dark matter",
        "By designing advanced propulsion systems",
        "By managing interactions between spacecraft and Earth's atmosphere"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "It relates to space exploration by working on creating sustainable ecosystems on other planets."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "7. What does 'Resilience Engineering' address in Earth Systems Engineering?",
      options: [
        "Predicting seismic activities",
        "Building structures resistant to extreme weather conditions",
        "Developing bioengineering systems",
        "Adapting to and recovering from disturbances"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "'Resilience Engineering' addresses adapting to and recovering from disturbances within Earth Systems Engineering."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "8. What's the role of 'Geospatial Engineering' in Earth Systems Engineering?",
      options: [
        "Creating detailed maps of other planets",
        "Developing renewable energy systems",
        "Analyzing and modeling spatial data for Earth's systems",
        "Predicting solar flares"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "'Geospatial Engineering' deals with analyzing and modeling spatial data for Earth's systems in Earth Systems Engineering."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "9. How does Earth Systems Engineering contribute to climate change mitigation?",
      options: [
        "By designing artificial weather control systems",
        "By developing clean energy solutions",
        "By conducting large-scale cloud seeding experiments",
        "By regulating ocean currents"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "It contributes by developing clean energy solutions for climate change mitigation."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "10. What role does 'Remote Sensing' play in Earth Systems Engineering?",
      options: [
        "Monitoring atmospheric conditions on Earth",
        "Predicting natural disasters on Earth",
        "Designing orbital satellite systems",
        "Modeling space debris"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "'Remote Sensing' monitors atmospheric conditions on Earth within Earth Systems Engineering."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "11. How does Earth Systems Engineering contribute to disaster management?",
      options: [
        "By studying plate tectonics",
        "By developing advanced early warning systems",
        "By analyzing Earth's mantle dynamics",
        "By managing space debris"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "It contributes by developing advanced early warning systems for disaster management."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "12. What is the primary goal of 'Earth Systems Modeling'?",
      options: [
        "Studying lunar surface conditions",
        "Designing advanced spacecraft",
        "Modeling the interactions of various Earth systems",
        "Analyzing the geological history of Earth"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "'Earth Systems Modeling' aims to model the interactions of various Earth systems."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "13. How does 'Ecological Engineering' fit into Earth Systems Engineering?",
      options: [
        "Designing underground biospheres",
        "Creating artificial ecosystems",
        "Developing advanced energy storage systems",
        "Balancing economic and environmental considerations"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "'Ecological Engineering' involves creating artificial ecosystems in Earth Systems Engineering."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "14. What is the focus of 'Space Habitat Design' in Earth Systems Engineering?",
      options: [
        "Designing spacecraft engines",
        "Developing artificial gravity systems",
        "Planning for human survival on other planets",
        "Modeling asteroid impact trajectories"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "'Space Habitat Design' focuses on planning for human survival on other planets within Earth Systems Engineering."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "15. How does Earth Systems Engineering relate to global agricultural systems?",
      options: [
        "By predicting crop yields",
        "By regulating atmospheric carbon levels",
        "By developing advanced irrigation systems",
        "By managing interactions between agriculture and environmental systems"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "It relates by managing interactions between agriculture and environmental systems."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "16. What does 'Socio-Technical Systems' refer to in Earth Systems Engineering?",
      options: [
        "Studying social dynamics of space colonization",
        "Analyzing human behavior in artificial ecosystems",
        "Developing advanced space propulsion systems",
        "Balancing social and technological elements in engineered systems"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "'Socio-Technical Systems' refers to balancing social and technological elements in engineered systems."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "17. How does 'Earth Systems Optimization' contribute to sustainability?",
      options: [
        "By analyzing extraterrestrial systems",
        "By developing energy-efficient space habitats",
        "By optimizing interactions between Earth systems",
        "By predicting celestial events"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "'Earth Systems Optimization' contributes by optimizing interactions between Earth systems for sustainability."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "18. What's the role of 'Biogeochemistry' in Earth Systems Engineering?",
      options: [
        "Designing spacecraft materials",
        "Studying biochemical processes on other planets",
        "Analyzing the interactions between living organisms and the environment",
        "Developing meteorological instruments"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "'Biogeochemistry' involves analyzing the interactions between living organisms and the environment in Earth Systems Engineering."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "19. How does Earth Systems Engineering address resource management?",
      options: [
        "By regulating extraterrestrial resource exploitation",
        "By optimizing resource utilization on Earth",
        "By studying planetary formations",
        "By developing space debris cleanup systems"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "It addresses by optimizing resource utilization on Earth."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "20. What is the focus of 'Planetary Engineering' within Earth Systems Engineering?",
      options: [
        "Developing advanced interstellar travel systems",
        "Creating artificial atmospheres on other planets",
        "Designing new habitats for space exploration",
        "Predicting extraterrestrial life forms"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "'Planetary Engineering' focuses on creating artificial atmospheres on other planets."
  ),


  ];